Hello, my name is Glinju, I am a health
insurance advisor, my hometown is Thrissur. As usual,
today is
a comparison video about health insurance policies,
especially health insurance policies that cover other expenses,
i.e. delivery expenses.
So if you are searching for health insurance, do not
skip this video and
try to watch it in its entirety. Often, when taking maternity-
related health insurance, one of the questions
asked is
how many months after maternity does the
coverage start. Similarly,
my wife has been caring for me for two months now, so is it
possible to take health insurance, and will the
insurance cover treatments like IVF?
So, on the
basis of that, we are going to go into today's
comparison video. For that,
we will take
five products today for comparison, the first of which is Nivappa's  The
plan called Asper, as
well as Star Health's Women Care, the
first one, Active One
Maternity Plan, and
two products of Renew Buy have been taken. The two products
called Macma and Liberty are products
of companies called Liberty.
So let's
take a look at the product.
One feature that we have taken for the first time is the
waiting period. The
waiting
period is a very important factor for maternity. If we look at Niboba's Asper, we have a
waiting period of nine months. In their
Platinum and Titanium,
after nine months, the metal expense is
covered. Similarly, if we
look at Star Health's plan, if we take a
policy of Rs. 15 lakhs or more in Women Care, we
get the metal expense covered even after one year and 12 months.
Similarly,
a product that was seen on many Instagrams recently was the
first one, the first one, Active One, which is a product that is sold through Policy Bazaar.  The
plan called Maternity has a big feature that
we will
get the expenses covered after three months,
especially for those who are carrying,
the company says that after taking this policy, we will get a claim.
Similarly, this policy
is a broking firm like the Bazaar, so
they sell through
Magma and Liberty.
These two insurances
cover maternity expenses for us.
In this, if it is in Magma, we
get maternity expenses covered after 12 months. Similarly, in
Liberty, we get
maternity expenses covered after nine months.
Similarly, the
next thing we have taken is
about maternity coverage. It is very
important how much coverage
we will get after taking the policy.
We should never think that if we take a
policy of 10 lakhs, if we
take health insurance, we will get 10 lakhs as
maternity expenses. There is
never a limit in this
maternity plan.
So if you look at the aspect of Niwopi, for those aged
10 to 35,
there is a 10X
coverage. They say that this is an
inbuilt feature in it. It
says that it is a miracle benefit. But in this, this amount has been set aside for each sum insured.
So if you
take 3 lakhs, you will get ₹4000 for
maternity in the first year.
Similarly, if you
take 5 lakhs, you will get ₹5000. If you take 10 lakhs, you will get ₹12000. If you take 20 lakhs,
you will
get 20000 above that. If you take 20000 above that, we will get ₹20000 as sum insured. On the
other hand, it will
become a 10X. So if you have taken 10 lakhs,
we will get ₹12000. So it is
called a 10X coverage. So we have ₹120000. By the end of 10
years, it will gradually increase.
I
think it is better if you take it before marriage.
This policy is a little better.
Similarly, if we come to Star Health's
Women Care, we get a
policy of 15 lakhs and
after one year we get covered up
to 50,000.
Similarly, if we
take a policy of 25 lakhs,
we get covered up to 75,000 as a deductible and expense. After
one year, similarly, if we
come for the first time, we
say 50,000. Even after three months,
as mentioned earlier, even if it is carrying,
we get coverage of ₹
50,000. If it is normal or if it is a
caesarean, we get ₹50,000.
Similarly, if we
look at the policy on renewal, even if these
two balls are in Macmala Liberty,
we
get ₹50,000 in both. After nine months,
another feature that needs to be taken care of is
newborn baby coverage. I think the
most important feature to take care of when
taking maternity coverage is this one
feature.  That is the reason why
congenital diseases are seen a lot in children born now, and there are a lot of
heart valve issues.
Similarly, when a
first-time baby is born, they have to
stay in the ICU a lot after birth. So it is better
to take a policy that provides such coverage. Because
we know that there is a limit in maternity coverage, a maximum of
50,000 or
1 lakh. We get the maximum in a metat and
coverage
policy. But when it
comes to newborn baby coverage,
policies are available in the market until we get up to sum insured. So the
reason why we say that is because the
chances of such things are very high.
I have been hearing a lot of cases of many children born now having valve issues like this.
So it would be better to choose
policies that provide newborn baby coverage. If you
look at it that way, if you look at
Nivopa's policy now, if you
look at Aspire, we get up to sum
insured.
In the policy, like Star
Health, we
get 25%, we get up to 25% of the sum insured
as newborn baby expenses.
Similarly, if we
look at Aditya Pillai's plan, Aditya and Macma
Liberty do not cover
newborn baby expenses in any of these three.
Similarly, many
people often ask when taking this type of policy, whether
treatment expenses like IVF are covered or not.
Of course, in all these
policies,
treatment like IVF is covered,
but they all say a limit, they say
an amount. Now, if we
look at the policy, we get up
to the sum insured of the miracle benefit,
that is, if we have taken ₹10 lakhs,
we will initially
get ₹12,000 that is covered in that maternal expense for this IVF treatment. Similarly, if we
look at Star Health, if we take it for 15 lakhs,
we
get coverage up to 1.5 lakhs, and if we
take it for 25 lakhs, we get coverage up to 2 lakhs for
IVF treatment.  Treatment
coverage is available but
this coverage starts after 36 months.
Similarly, the first and
remaining Macma Libate do not
provide treatment coverage like IVF. Similarly,
one thing that we all want to hear is the
premium. In this,
we take a premium for 35-30 year olds. If we
come to Niwap, the premium
comes to ₹15282 for 10 lakhs without adding any riders.
Similarly, if we
look at Star Health,
we take 15 lakhs.
Why do we take 15 lakhs? If we
take 15 lakhs, we get maternity coverage after one year for poles above 15 lakhs. If we take poles below 15, the maternity wait period is two years. The
premium comes to
₹21783. So,
Aditya Pillai's product is sold through Pole Bazaar.
It has only come on four platforms.  On a negative note, I
think we have to take the premium for three years
together,
so the premium for us is
around ₹58270 for a
coverage of 10 lakhs. Similarly,
renew by this policy is a broking firm like Bazaar. There, a
company called Magma is said to be offering
maternity coverage in the same way. If
we take it for 2 lakhs, it will
come close to ₹9833, but we will
get maternity coverage of ₹50000.
Similarly, if we take Liberty, we will get a coverage of
₹11902 for a coverage of 4 lakhs.
So, as mentioned,
we will get ₹50000 coverage.
So, I think that now
we have a health insurance. If we
have health insurance from any other company, we can
take these policies as an add-on,
especially if we
want a separate add-on for a name like Maxmed Liberator. Of course, in
my
personal view, most of them are  If you
are looking for health insurance, especially for those who are looking for
a little extra, it would be better to take out health insurance that covers newborn baby expenses.
So, if you have any doubts like this,
you can feel
free to contact me.
My WhatsApp number is
given below. If you have any doubts, you can
call me from that number.
Thank you, greetings, dear ones. If you
like the videos of Katukumani, you should join me.